- During this part of the course,
we will be getting more familiar with some
of the most well-known types of generative AI models,
and some of the applications they cover.
Think of generative AI models,
let's use the metaphor, food.
Under the term food,
you find salads, soups, caviar, stews, fresh vegetables,
and just like food,
under the umbrella term of generative AI,
you find several options
depending on what you are craving for.
So this isn't meant to be an exhaustive list
of all the applications and all the models,
but think of it more like a guide
to the generative AI landscape
and how you can make use of it.
But keep in mind
that this landscape is changing dramatically
every single day.
And there's a very good chance
that when you're watching this course,
there will be lots and lots of new players, models,
and applications already born.
But that's what makes it so exciting.
So let's start exploring some of the main models together.