- The advent of generative AI can be likened
to the invention of photography and celluloid film,
a true creative revolution.
With photography, we no longer needed to rely
on the interpretation of an artist to capture reality,
and with generative AI,
we no longer need artistic talent to draw or to sing.
We can access now concise information
in just a manner of seconds.
We can also automatically generate text
such as news articles or product descriptions.
We can even design custom products like shoes or furniture.
We can produce music, speech, visual effects,
3D assets and sound effects using algorithms trained
on already existing data.
I know you're like, it all sounds magic, doesn't it?
Yeah, it does.
But like Arthur C. Clark said, any sufficiently
advanced technology is simply undistinguishable from magic.
These machines are becoming 24 hours, seven assistants
ready to perform a variety of tasks for us, resulting
in the manifestation of our vision almost in real time.
By training on large data sets, we can reduce the burden
of repetitive tasks and complex computations, enabling us to
focus on more creative and more strategic activities
which is the very essence of what work is really about.
The development of generative AI has a very rich
and very fascinating history marked
by significant breakthroughs, even though it
gained widespread attention in 2022, its evolution was built
on decades of mathematical research,
starting with auto encoder neural networks in 2006
and continuing on through the mass adoption
of generative AI models like DALL E, ChatGPT by Open ai,
Kubrick, Journey and others today.
Not only have the providers and services expanded
but the quality of what is being produced has
improved drastically as well.
Like you can see in this chart by our world in data
the exponential improvement in the quality
of images generated between 2014 and 2022.
While the pictures in 2014 are black and white
and extremely pixelated.
In 2022, we would simply
type any word on the screen and generate coherent outcomes.
Generative AI is not only changing almost
every single profession, but it is also changing
our understanding of what work is.
Large parts of the production process that are repetitive
or can be computational are now starting to be facilitated
by AI models.
All of this leads to the chance
we are given to discover the essence
of what it means to be a human and the true meaning of work.
A beautiful new existence awaits us where we focus
on what makes us unique as a species, our curiosity,
our conscious awareness, our dreams,
our emotional intelligence, and our vision
while the algorithms we have created assist us
in the production and the execution of our authentic vision.