- When starting to work with generative AI,
it's imperative that we hold conscious contemplations
for the future of jobs.
As you know, there's a lot of hype at the moment
filled with a lot of Hollywood-powered fear
that machines are now taking over.
This is simply not true.
If anyone is taking over,
it is us humans who are entering in a new golden age
for creativity and production.
Will there be a shift in the job market?
Yeah, absolutely, as it has always been throughout history.
Whenever a new advanced technology is introduced,
it's normal for some jobs to disappear,
while other new ones are introduced.
Let's give an example.
Before alarm clocks, there were knocker uppers.
These were kids who were hired to knock on the windows
to wake people up.
The job obviously disappeared when new job opportunities
for alarm clock manufacturers emerged.
The second example would be the switchboard operator jobs.
They disappeared due to the widespread adoption
of automated telephone exchange systems,
and even though it made jobs disappear,
automated telephone exchange systems
revolutionized communication
and connected people all across the world.
What if I were to tell you
that there's a very high possibility
that certain parts of your job that are repetitive,
dirty, dull, dangerous, or difficult,
the four D's, can be automated?
As a result, you will have more time
focusing parts of your skills that are more human-centric,
like creativity, problem solving,
empathy, and leadership.
Just like the digital revolution in the 90s
gave birth to the emergence of new companies,
we're now witnessing several new endeavors
due to the generative AI revolution.
As the co-founder of a generative AI-powered
creative company, let me assure you
that all our operations are run by humans.
Our company employs developers, cloud architects,
generative AI artists, customer relations,
project managers, writers, creative directors,
and human producers.
If the Industrial Revolution created jobs
that were robotic for humans,
the Generative AI Revolution will be our liberation
and freedom from them.
Each person will turn into their own creative studio
and the barriers between your vision
and its manifestation will disappear.
Complex films, music, writing,
and all forms of creative production tools
will be simplified and given to your fingertips.
Humanity will transcend from a society of consumers
to creators.
The ones that excel in the future of job markets
will be those that strengthen
their unique personal emotional skills
that no computer can ever mimic.
My advice would be to start investing
in expanding your consciousness,
start getting to know what makes you unique,
and sharpen your interpersonal, emotional,
and creative skills.