- The best way to predict the future,
as they say, is to invent it so let's talk about the future.
In two to three years in the gaming,
film and marketing sectors generative AI
will continue to be used in computer graphics,
and animation to create more realistic,
and believable characters, and environments.
This is going to be particularly important in 3D modeling.
Generative AI will be used to improve
natural language understanding in virtual assistants
and chatbots making them more and more capable
of handling complex and nuanced conversations.
In the energy sector, generative AI models
will be used to optimize energy consumption
and production, such as predicting demand,
and managing renewable energy sources, as well as improving
the efficiency of energy distribution networks.
As for the transportation sector, generative AI models
will be used to optimize traffic flow
and to predict maintenance needs for vehicles.
In short, generative AI will be used
to automate repetitive tasks and improve efficiency
in a wide variety of industries.
My predictions for the next 10 to 15 years
would be generative AI will be used to create
more and realistic, and accurate simulations in fields
such as architecture, urban planning, and engineering.
The second would be to be used to create
new materials and products in fields,
such as manufacturing and textile design.
The third will be natural language generation
will be improved in the fields of content creation
such as news articles, books, and even movie scripts.
It will also improve self-driving cars
by generating realistic virtual scenarios
for testing and training, and also it will excel
in audio to asset generation where you can speak,
and then have the AI generate an asset.
In short, my prediction for the upcoming
10 to 15 years would be generative AI
will be used in the creation and production
of mass media quality books, films, and games.
Meanwhile, it will also be the technology
behind paradigm shifting implications
in the job market, such as self-driving cars,
advanced robotics for manufacturing, and for warehousing,
and improved crop yield and precision agriculture.