- Generative AI is changing how we create.
(light music)
For the first time,
humans are supervising
and machines are generating.
It's helping us lift the dirty, dull,
dangerous and difficult tasks from humanity's shoulders
so then we can simply focus on the very essence
of our work,
the vision, the idea, and the purpose.
It's a complete paradigm shift for the future of jobs.
I am Pinar Seyhan Demirdag and I'm the co-founder
and the AI director of Seyhan Lee.
During this LinkedIn Learning course,
we will talk about how to use that tool
to drive the creation of your intention.
Join me as we dive deep
into this new creative revolution that I'm so excited about
and let's discover together
how each of us can have a place
in this age of advanced technologies.