- In 2022, we have seen a rise
in commercial image generation services.
The technology behind these services is broadly referred
as text to image.
You simply type words on a screen
and watch the algorithms create an image
based on your queue,
even if you description is not very specific.
There are three main text to image generation services.
Midjourney, DALL-E, and Stable Diffusion.
If we were to compare these three text to image tools
to operating systems, Midjourney would be macOS
because they have a closed API
and a very design and art-centric approach
to the image generation process.
DALL-E would be Windows but with an open API
because the model is released by a corporation
and it initially had the most superior
machine-learning algorithm.
Open AI values technical superiority
over design and art sensitivities.
And the third, the Stable Diffusion would be Linux
because it is open source
and is improving each day
with the contribution of the generative AI community.
The quality of the generated images
from text to image models can depend
both on the quality of the algorithm
and the datasets they use to train it.
So now that we know the main services,
let's look at three industrial applications.
First is Cuebric.
Hollywood's first generative AI tool created
by our company, Seyhan Lee,
for streaming the production of film backgrounds.
A normal virtual production workflow
uses three dimensional world building
which involves a bunch of people building 3D worlds
that are custom made for that film.
It's time consuming, expensive,
and requires a lot of repetitive tasks.
An alternative now is to augment 2D backgrounds into 2.5D
by involving generative AI in the picture creation process.
The second example would be Stitch Fix.
When they suggest garments
to discover their customer's fashion style,
they use real clothes
along with clothes generated with DALL-E.
And finally, marketers and filmmakers
use text to image models
when ideating for a concept in a film.
And actually, they may later on continue to use it
to make storyboards
and even use it in the production
of the final art of their campaigns and films.
Just like we have seen in Cuebric.
A recent example from the marketing world would be Martini
that used the Midjourney generated image
in their campaign.
Another one would be Heinz and Nestle
that used DALL-E in their campaign.
And GoFundMe that used Stable Diffusion
in their artfully illustrated film.
Marketers prefer using generative AI
in their creative process for two reasons.
First, for its time and cost-saving efficiency,
and the second, for the unique look and feel
that you get from text to image based tools.