- Any executive or business leader
should approach generative AI tools with caution.
We should at all times self-monitor
and self-question if the generated results
fits our quality and satisfaction parameters.
Just because ChatGPT generates headlines,
it doesn't mean that what it makes is great.
Or just because we can generate a landscape
with Stable Diffusion,
it doesn't mean it's ready for the final pixel of a movie.
During this grace period
where we learn to co-create with algorithms,
it's crucial that we deepen our executive skills.
If we are a founder or an executive
in a generative AI company,
we shall, at all times,
always ask ourselves who is benefiting from our tools?
Our moral compass should always direct towards transparency,
fairness, empathy, and responsibility.
I highly recommend organizing a board or a council
at your organization that acts like the ethical foundation
for the integration of generative ai.
Provide, please, all your employees with ethical guidance
and education on how to use generative AI effectively,
and also how to overcome their fears, challenges, and biases
towards this new advanced tool.
As the technology continues to evolve,
it's very likely that the distinction
between human and algorithm-generated content
will become increasingly blurred,
and it will become even more important
for leaders like you to have a clear understanding
of the role of each.
We will remain in control of AI by always positioning
the human consciousness in the very center
of generative AI companies and solutions.
Especially in our organizations,
we must ensure that humans remain the sole decision makers.
In this way, we will be setting the objectives
and determine the direction of AI-generated content.
By keeping humans at the very center,
we can ensure that the content produced
by generative AI aligns with your company values and goals,
which have to do with serving the elation
and elevation of humanity.
By actively engaging with generative AI technology
and developing a deep understanding of its capabilities
and limitations all across your team,
we can avoid the potential risks
associated with blindly relying on AI
to make decisions for us.
Well, ultimately, the goal is to strike a beautiful balance
between leveraging the power of generative AI
to enhance human creativity and imagination,
and optimizing production,
while also maintaining human control and oversight
over this advanced technology.