- Let's now move to talking about an application
of generative AI that may not be as obvious
as it's used in generating images,
like we have seen earlier, audio or text.
But it's still very important application nonetheless,
and it is going to be the anomaly detection.
One of the main models that we use
in this space is Variational Autoencoders,
referred as VAE.
These models can be used for anomaly detection
by training the model on a dataset of normal data,
and then using the trained model to identify instances
that deviate from the normal data.
This can be used to detect anomalies
in a wide range of situations, like finding fraud
in financial transactions, spotting flaws in manufacturing
or finding security breaches in a network.
For example, Uber has used VAE for anomaly detection
in their financial transactions to detect fraud.
Another example would be Google has also used VAE
to detect network intrusions using anomaly detection
and another one of a real world application of VAE
would be anomaly detection in industrial quality control.
In this scenario, a VAE can be trained
on a dataset of images of normal products
and then used to identify images of products
that deviate from the normal data.
In this way, it can be used to detect defects
in products such as scratches, dents, or misalignments.
Another real world example would be healthcare
where VAE is used to detect anomalies
in medical imaging such as CT scans and MRI,
like Children's National Hospital in Washington, DC
uses a generative AI model
to analyze electronic health records.
The model uses data such as vital signs, laboratory results
and demographic information to predict which patients
are at risk of sepsis,
allowing healthcare providers to intervene early
and improve patient outcomes.
Variational Autoencoders are a flexible,
generative model that are not only able to detect anomalies
but are also a part of the architecture
of several other generative AI models.