- So now that we have our generative AI model
and our chassis,
we are ready to create our own content.
If we're a beginner,
we can use a paid service like Midjourney or Lensa.
If we are more experienced,
we can use a notebook and pick from available models.
If you download a commercial app
and upload only 10 pictures of yourself, like I did,
the app suggests a variety of different avatars of yourself.
It's super fun.
If you are a more experienced generative AI user,
a creative technologist, you can go to GitHub,
choose your favorite generative AI model,
and see if it is available in the form of a notebook.
If it's not available, you can still inquire about it
inside the generative AI community.
They're super friendly people.
And if you are a programmer,
you can also create your own notebook
by taking the model code from GitHub.
For a demonstration,
we will be running a Google Colab notebook named Deforum,
that is based on stable diffusion,
to generate a fantasy landscape.
As you can see here, the notebook runs through the code,
and depending on your settings,
produces a personalized outcome.
Google Colab requires a subscription.
If you would like your generation time to be minimized
you need to buy a paid subscription.
These notebooks offer a lot of personalized options
for the quality of your outcomes.
You can always choose the default generation,
but the beauty of working with a notebook
is that you can tweak and personalize the outcomes.
In summary, a model is a set of algorithms
that have been trained on a specific dataset.
A notebook is a tool for writing and running the code.
A creative application is an example
of how a model can be used,
and the generated outcome is what the end user produces
by using a generative AI service
or a notebook that houses the model inside it.