- I want to round out this course
with a controversial statement.
The greatest bias in AI is not race,
is not ethnicity, nor gender.
It is human's inferiority complex.
If we see machines as superior to humans,
we place them on a pedestal,
and if we see humans
as incapable fragile beings,
we again place AI on a pedestal,
but this time with the power of an authority.
We should always emphasize the crucial and essential role
of human creativity and decision-making in the process.
Nowadays, popular headlines suggest that AI is designing,
AI is coding,
but let's remember, it's humans who wrote the algorithms
for AI, and it's humans who conceptualize, curate,
and oversee the algorithms to produce the desired outcomes.
If we place AI and technology at the center
of our workflow in storytelling,
we risk dehumanizing ourselves and contributing
to a future where human jobs may really be eliminated.
Instead, we should focus on highlighting
the central role that humans play
in the creation and the use of AI.
I know even though sentences
such as like, "AI made this art,
and, "AI is advancing quickly,
AI is so cool," are common in the collective,
we should strive to correct ourselves
in centering our actions and self-expression around humans.
It is humans that are making art
by using generative AI-powered tools, and it is,
again, humans that are working in tandem with each other
to advance several different human-benefiting technologies,
including generative AI.
By modeling our tools after ourselves,
we are inevitably transferring our own judgments,
our own insecurities,
and our own limitations onto this technology.
So it is essential
that we work to overcome our own insecurities
and approach AI as a tool that can augment
and empower us, rather than compete or replace us.
By doing so, we can create AI systems that contribute
to the elation of humanity,
assist us with creative productivity,
and help us achieve our greatest potential as a species.